OP
虫奉行をぶっ殺せ！
俺たちの宿願は目の前だ
Our goal lies right before us.
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Kill the Insect Magistrate!
The Insect Magistrate is
staying at Hachijo Island.
八丈島にお籠りの虫奉行さまを
蟲狩という者たちが狙っている
And a group, the Insect Hunters, is after her.
小鳥殿　それはまことですか？
Is that true, Kotori-dono?
しかし　我ら市中見廻組に加え 武家見廻組
If they're sending us, the city patrol,
with the Samurai House Patrol
寺社見廻組まで駆けつけねばならぬとは
and Shrine and Temple Patrol,
江戸の守りが
who will protect Edo?
いいかい　仁兵衛くん
Listen to me, Jinbei-kun...
If anything were to happen
to the Insect Magistrate,
もし虫奉行さまに万が一のことがあれば
江戸は一夜で無人の荒野になる
Edo would be flattened within a single night.
なっ　え　江戸が
I-It would?
The Insect Hunters Attack!!
Battle of Hachijo Island!!
Port of Edo
おお　なんと
What?
大きな船ですね
This ship is huge!
虫奉行所専用の大型弁才船だよ
【弁才船：中世末期至明治时期 日本国内海运广为使用的大型木造帆船】
It's the Insect Magistrate's personal ship.
直ちに出港
Cast off at once!
A huge insect, now of all times?
こんなときに巨大虫が
あそこは　お春殿の家があるあたり
That's near Oharu-dono's house...
時間がない　直ちに出港せよ
There isn't time. Launch immediately.
おいおい　あの虫はどうすんだよ
Hey, what about the insect?
今の我らの務めは虫奉行様を不逞の輩よりお守りすることだ
Right now, our job is to protect the Magistrate.
悪いが少しの間　痛みを耐えし呑んでもらうしかない
I'm sorry, but they'll have to suffer for a while.
ならば　自分が
Then I will...
辛いだろうが　いまの我らには別のお務めがあるんだ
I'm sure it's difficult, but we have
another task at the moment.
小鳥殿
Kotori-dono!
O-Oharu-dono...
お春殿
その雑用　拙者ども 武家見廻組が引き受けよう
We, the Samurai House Patrol,
will handle this task.
尾上殿
Ogami-dono!
将軍家のお膝元に虫どもをのさばらせるなど
We cannot leave an insect alone
at the base of the Shogun's palace.
一時たりとも言語道断
尾上影忠率いる　武家見廻組一同
Ogami Kagetada and his patrol group
will gladly attend to this task,
as servants of the shogunate!
将軍の犬として　喜んで雑用仕る
尾上殿　お江戸を頼みます
Ogami-dono, please save Edo!
それではゆくぞ　皆の者　目指すは八丈島
Let us go, then...
We head for Hachijo Island!
Hachijo Island
Our goal lies before us.
俺たちの宿願は目の前だ
Kill the Insect Magistrate!
虫奉行をぶっ殺せ
島影が見えてきたぞ
The island's coming into view!
What? That's Hachijo Island?
なんと　あれが八丈島
The Insect Magistrate is there, right?
虫奉行様があそこにいらっしゃるのですね
ああ　シニタイ
I want to die...
Manako.
未那蚕　やはり貴様らか
Then it was you?
So the traitor leads the way?
裏切り者が先導者ってな
Manako
なんと
What?
ウソでしょ　まさか無涯さんと渡り合うなんて
No way...
He's evenly matched with Mugai-san?
He's as good as Mugai-dono?
あの無涯殿と　おのれ　何者だ
Exactly who are you?
なんだよ無涯　こいつらにゃまだなんにも言ってねえのかよ
What's this, Mugai?
You still haven't told them anything?
ハ　俺は未那蚕　蟲狩だ
I'm Manako... Of the Insect Hunters.
蟲狩
Insect Hunters?
だーリい
Tired...
今頃仲間が虫奉行を殺してっかもな
Perhaps my friends have killed
the Insect Magistrate by now.
なんと　虫奉行さまを殺すのが目的
What?
Your goal is to kill the Insect Magistrate?
どけ　無涯
Out of the way, Mugai!
Insect Hunters...
蟲狩
君のお母さんを手にかけたのは 蟲狩という連中だ
A group known as the
Insect Hunters killed your mother.
十年前　恋川左之助の女房　お菊を殺したのはテメエか
Was it you who killed the wife
of Koikawa Sanosuke,
Okiku, ten years ago?
I have no idea what you're talking about!
わけ分かんねえよ
みんな急いで
Hurry, everyone!
行かせるわけにはいかねんだよ
I can't let you go.
Bastard!
野郎
私たちは無事よ
We're fine!
こっちも
So are we.
火鉢くん　仁兵衛くん　先に行ってくれ
Hibachi-kun and Jinbei-kun, go on ahead.
こちらもすぐに行く
We'll catch up!
わかったわ
Got it.
お任せください
Leave it to us!
もう一人も逃がしやしねえ
I won't let anyone else escape.
俺はよ　実はもう死にてんだ
You see... I want to die.
この不条理だらけの世界で生き長らえるなんて
Living in this insane world is torture for me.
俺には拷問だよ
だからよ　一刻も早く虫奉行を殺して楽になるためによ
So I want
to kill the Insect Magistrate as soon
as possible and find peace.
ゴミ掃除を買って出たわけだ
For that, I volunteered to take out the trash.
もう少しで俺はようやくこの世からおさらばできる
It won't be long before I can bid this world farewell!
Will you kill me?
オマエ　俺を殺してくれる
答えろ　お菊を殺したのはテメエか
Answer me!
Did you kill Okiku?
狙いおお外しじゃん
You missed... Too bad.
No, I didn't.
狙い通りよ
どうだ　砲弾の味は
How do you like the cannons?
けっ　死ぬには
Not enough to kill me...
I won't change my title of Killer of 99,
for killing a loser like you.
雑魚を切って　九十九斬りの二つ名を返上するわけにはいかねんだよ
There he is!
来た
恋川くん
Koikawa-kun!
さあ　急ごうぜ　小鳥ちゃん
Let's hurry, Kotori-chan.
どうやら　この島に不審者が忍び込んだか
It appears we have intruders on this island.
すまぬ　八丈島の命たちよ
I'm sorry to all the creatures
that live on Hachijo Island.
待て
Wait.
What is it, leader?
なんだよリーダー　ビビってんのか
Are you scared?
虫が泣き止んだ
The insects stopped chirping.
The insects?
虫が
毒霧だ
Poison fog.
マジかよ
Seriously?
全員　解毒丸を飲め
Everyone, drink your antidotes.
行くぜ　この毒霧の奥に　虫奉行が居る
Let's go.
The Insect Magistrate is within this poison fog.
な　月島　あんたどこつかんでんのよ
Hey!
Tsukishima, what are you grabbing?
放しなさいよ
Let go of me.
無理です　死んでしまいます
I can't...
I'll die!
What?
なんと　あの霧はなんでしょう
What is that fog?
知らないわよ
I don't know.
気張っていくわよ
Stay sharp.
わたしたちが先陣なんだから
We're the first ones here.
火鉢殿　お任せください
Hibachi-dono, leave it to me!
この月島仁兵衛　粉骨砕身火鉢殿の足を引っ張らないよう致します
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall do everything
in my power to not slow you down!
だから　どこ握ってんの
Where are your hands?
Those are the Insect Hunters?
あの者達が蟲狩
月島
Tsukishima?
いててて
O-Ow...
Y-You're...
あなたは…
以前蟲奉行所で会ったお嬢さん
You're the girl I met
at the Insect Magistrate's!
分かりました
I understand.
ここにいるということは…
If you're here, you must be a
servant of the Magistrate.
あなたは蟲奉行様のお付の方だったんですね
No, I'm...
いや　わらわは…
Miss, I'm sorry, but I have an
urgent matter to discuss...
お付の方　すみませんが　火急の用です
蟲奉行様はどちらに？
Where is the Magistrate?
I am...
わらわが…
I see...
そうですか
蟲奉行様は今お出かけなのですね
The Magistrate is not here, then?
No, I am...
いや　わらわが…
Right.
そうですか
お付の方もこれから蟲奉行様の所へ向かわれるわけですね
So you're heading out to find
the Magistrate now, aren't you?
わらわは…
I am...
Yes.
うむ　実はそうなのだ
Actually, you're right.
おぉ　やはり
I knew it!
Let's hurry, then.
では急ぎましょう
蟲狩という者達がすぐそこまで来て
A group called the Insect Hunters is almost here.
お命を狙っているのです
They're after the Magistrate's life.
その必要はない
There is no need to worry.
No one could make it here
through that poisonous fog.
毒霧で覆われたここに来る者など　まずないからな
そうなのですか
I suppose so...
But the Magistrate...
ですが　蟲奉行様は
その…
is...
in a safe place.
安全な所にいる
紫陽花玉
Hydrangea Blossoms.
I won't stand here and let you attack me.
一々受けんのもうぜんだよ
Mashiro
爆発を蹴りの衝撃波で受けるなんて
She blocked the explosions with
the shock wave from her kicks?
This is the Insect Hunters' power,
これが蟲狩の実力だ
stupid, weird-faced girl.
ちんくしゃバカ女
ちん　ちんくしゃ？
W-Weird-faced?
You're a flat-chested four-eyes!
何を　この貧乳メガネ
You shouldn't have said that.
お前　地雷踏んだな
甲脚
Armor Kick!
このような命のにおいがまったくしない場所で
So the Insect Magistrate spends the summers here,
蟲奉行様は… 夏の間ここに一人でおられたのですね
in this place devoid of life...
あのう　お付の方　蟲奉行様とは一体 どのようなお方なのでしょうか
Um, miss, what is the Insect Magistrate like?
Well, I suppose I could tell you a bit.
ま　少しぐらいはよいか
蟲奉行は…
The Magistrate is...
自分はきっと　とても大柄でお強くて逞しく
I picture someone very big and strong,
修行僧のように己に厳しい方だと思うのですが
and quite disciplined, like a Buddhist priest.
うむ　そうだな
Yes, you're right.
おぉ　やはり
I knew it!
I guess it doesn't matter.
まあ　よいか
それぐらいお強い方でなければ
Without that kind of strength,
このような場所にお一人だなんて寂しくていられないですよね
no one would last in a lonely place like this!
もしかしたら　寂しいなどとは少しも思わず
It's possible the Magistrate doesn't find it lonely at all.
and would prefer to stay here all the time.
蟲奉行はずっとここにいたいと思っているやもしれぬぞ
蟲奉行には自由などない
The Magistrate has no freedom.
江戸では御簾の奥から出ることさえ難しい
When in Edo, it is difficult to even
come outside the bamboo shades.
だが少なくともここでは　見上げればいつでも空を見ることができる
But here, one can always see the sky.
正直　今のお話はよく分かりませんでしたが
To be honest, I don't really understand all that.
これだけは自信を持って言えます
But I can say this for sure...
一人でこの空を見上げるより
Looking at the sky here
江戸で皆と一緒に見上げる青空のほうが
won't make you nearly as happy as it would
if you were with everyone in Edo!
ずっとずっと元気が出ます
When he looks at the sky,
he probably always feels that way.
この者は　いつもそう思って空を見上げているのだろうな
そう感じているこの者が　少し羨ましい
And that makes me envy him a little.
If someone like you were
by the side of the Insect Magistrate,
蟲奉行も　もしお主のような者がそばにいれば
少しは退屈せずにすむかもしれんな
perhaps things would not be so boring.
At last we meet, Insect Magistrate.
ようやく会えたな　蟲奉行
それじゃ　あばよ
Now, goodbye!
酸性の毒か
Acidic poison?
貴様
You bastard!
消えた
He disappeared?
霧が消えていく
The fog is disappearing!
I won't let you pass.
お前らこっから先には行かせねぇから
Kuroganemaru
Whoever killed her was good.
下手人は腕の立つやつ
A group known as the
Insect Hunters killed your mother.
君のお母さんを手にかけたのは
蟲狩という連中だ
The Insect Hunters?
蟲狩？
君も薄々分かっていたんじゃないのか
You noticed it, didn't you?
Only someone very skilled
could have cut like that.
あの太刀筋は相当腕が立つ人間でないと無理だよ
This wimp can only fire a gun.
撃つことしか能がねぇ小者は
お袋の敵じゃねぇってか
He didn't kill my mom, then.
Hey, Tenma! You take this wimp!
おい　天間　後は頼んだぜ
死ねよ
Die...
急々如律令
Do my bidding!
Tamekichi, Full-Power Slap!
為吉　全力突っ張り
Matsukichi, do my bidding!
末吉  急々如律令
I won't fall for that again!
二度と同じ手食うかよ
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
末吉　為吉
そろそろ　仕舞いにするか
Come... Let us end this.
待て　蟲狩共
Wait, Insect Hunters!
これより先は　この月島仁兵衛が相手だ
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall be your opponent.
Miss, are you safe?
お付の方　ご無事ですか
後はお任せください
Leave them to me...
あなたは一刻も早く蟲奉行様の所へ
You get to the Magistrate!
What horrible timing...
何と間が悪いのだ
I moved the fight away
to avoid getting you caught up in it.
わざわざ遠く離れてお主を巻き添えにせぬようにしているのに
死ね
Die!
Here they come.
Let's go, Insect Hunters!
行くぞ　蟲狩
What?
何と？！
止めろ
Stop!
Not again.
この者はまた　早く離れねば
I must get away now!
I don't understand.
どうも消せぬ
どういうことなのだ
What is this?
This isn't like normal.
いつもとは明らかに調子がおかしい
The Insect Hunters are here to kill me,
わらわを殺しに来た蟲狩共がいるというのに
別のことばかりに気をとられている
but I can only think of something else.
Why?
一体なぜ
Miss, are you hurt?
お付の方　大事はないですか
That's it...
そうだ
わらわは先程よりこの月島という者のことばかり考えさせられている
Right now, the only thing I can
think of is this Tsukishima.
Hello again, Mugai.
久しぶりだな　無涯
I never thought the day would
come when I'd fight you...
まさかお前とやり合う時が来ようとはな
Gaikotsu
秘剣　血飛沫
Secret Blade: Blood Splatter!
腕は鈍ってないようだな
I guess you're still as good as when
you were leader of the Insect Hunters.
さすが元蟲狩リーダー
Mugai...
無涯
What does he mean you were
leader of the Insect Hunters?
蟲狩のリーダーってのはどういう意味だ
Did you
お前が
kill my mother?!
お袋を殺したのか？
Next Time
白い花　白い砂　白い波　白い雲
White flowers, white sand,
white waves, white clouds.
いや　あそこを飛ぶのは火鉢殿
No, Hibachi-dono is flying over there.
白いですね　ふんどしが
Her underwear is white!
ちょっ　見るな
Stop staring!
次回　蟲奉行「黒揚羽降臨」
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
Kuroageha Arrives
Kuroageha Arrives.